Punishment comes one way or another.
True Grit is a drama, adventure, western film directed by Ethan Coen.
Following the murder of her father by a hired hand, a
14-year-old farm girl sets out to capture the killer.
To aid her, she hires the toughest U.S.
Marshal she can find—a man with 'true grit'—Reuben J.
'Rooster' Cogburn.
Rooster Cogburn, played by Jeff Bridges.
Mattie Ross, played by Hailee Steinfeld.
LaBoeuf, played by Matt Damon.
Tom Chaney, played by Josh Brolin.
Lucky Ned Pepper, played by Barry Pepper.
Col. Stonehill, played by Dakin Matthews.
True Grit is a 2010 American Western film produced, written,
and directed by Joel Coen and Ethan Coen.
It is an adaptation of Charles Portis's 1968 novel.
Starring Jeff Bridges and Hailee Steinfeld (in her theatrical film debut),
True Grit also stars Matt Damon, Josh Brolin, and Barry Pepper.
In the film, 14-year-old farm girl Mattie Ross (Steinfeld) hires boozy, trigger-happy lawman Rooster Cogburn (Bridges) to go after outlaw Tom Chaney
(Brolin), who murdered her father, accompanied by Texas Ranger LaBoeuf (Damon), who is also hunting Chaney, and who has his own gripes with Cogburn.
The Coens intended their film to be a more faithful adaptation of Portis's novel than the 1969 version
starring John Wayne; in particular, they wanted to tell the story from Mattie's point of view.
The casting call for the role of Mattie received some 15,000
applicants before Steinfeld was selected.
Principal photography occurred mainly in the Santa Fe,
New Mexico, area in March–April 2010.
True Grit was shot by cinematographer Roger Deakins and scored by composer Carter Burwell—both Coen
regulars—while the brothers themselves edited the film, under the Roderick Jaynes pseudonym.
True Grit was released in theatres in the United States by
Paramount Pictures on December 22, 2010.
The film grossed $252 million worldwide on a $35–38 million production budget, and was very well received by critics, with particular praise
for its acting, directing, writing, score, and production values, with some deeming it superior to the earlier adaptation.
Rated one of the best films of 2010, True Grit received several awards and nominations; at the 83rd
Academy Awards, it received 10 nominations, including Best Picture, but won none.
The film explores themes of bounty hunter, based on novel or book,
father murder, loss of loved one, texas ranger.
The tone is emotional.